Inventory of the Rikugun records
Hoover Institution Archives
Rikugun records
1944-1946
2007C52
Japan. Rikugun.
52 oversize boxes (31 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives
Surveys of buildings and other property in China.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2007.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Rikugun Records consists of documents prepared by the Headquarters of the Post-War Demobilization of the Japanese Armies Dispatched to China during 1944-1946. The materials, arranged by field army name, include checklists, surveys, maps and records of buildings and other cultural properties seized by the Japanese Imperial Army.
Japan--Armed Forces--China.
- First Army Records, 1944-1946
  - Chinese Properties Unit, 1944
    - Vol. 1 (Box 1-2)
  - Other Units, 1946
    - Vol. 1 (Box 3-4, 41)
    - Vol. 2 (Box 3-4, 41)
    - Vol. 4 (Box 3-4, 41)
  - Warehouse, Hospitals, Dormitories and Airports Units, 1946
    - Vol. 2 (Box 3-4, 41)
- Sixth Army Records, 1945-1946
  - United Nations Properties Unit, 1946
    - Vol. 2 (Box 5)
  - Unit 2 and Unit 3, 1945
    - Vol. 2 (Box 5)
  - Japanese Properties Unit, 1946
    - Vol. 2 (Box 6-7)
    - Vol. 6 (Box 6-7)
    - Vol. 7 (Box 6-7)
    - Vol. 9 (Box 6-7)
    - Vol. 10 (Box 8-10)
    - Vol. 16 (Box 8-10)
    - Vol. 18 (Box 8-10)
  - Chinese Properties Unit, 1946
    - Vol. 1 (Box 11-12)
    - Vol. 3 (Box 11-12)
    - Vol. 4 (Box 11-12)
    - Vol. 7 (Box 13-14)
    - Vol. 8 (Box 13-14)
    - Vol. 9 (Box 15-16)
    - Vol. 11 (Box 15-16)
    - Vol. 21 (Box 15-16)
    - Vol. 25 (Box 17-18)
    - Vol. 26 (Box 17-18)
    - Vol. 30 (Box 17-18)
    - Vol. 32 (Box 19)
    - Vol. 38 (Box 19)
  - Other Units, 1946
    - Vol. 5 (Box 42)
    - Vol. 6 (Box 42)
    - Vol. 7 (Box 42)
    - Vol. 8 (Box 42)
    - Vol. 9 (Box 42)
    - Vol. 15 (Box 42)
    - Vol. 10 (Box 42)
    - Vol. 15 (Box 42)
    - Vol. 16 (Box 43)
    - Vol. 17 (Box 43)
    - Vol. 18 (Box 43)
    - Vol. 19 (Box 43)
    - Vol. 20 (Box 43)
    - Vol. 21 (Box 43)
    - Vol. 22 (Box 20, 41)
    - Vol. 27 (Box 20, 41)
    - Vol. 30 (Box 20, 41)
- Eleventh Army Records, 1946
  - United Nations Properties Unit, 1946
    - Vol. 1 (Box 21-23)
- Twelfth Army Records, 1946
  - Chinese Property Unit, 1946
    - Vol. 1 (Luoyang) (Box 21-23)
    - Vol. 4 (Xuzhou) (Box 21-23)
  - Other Units, 1946
    - Vol. 20 (Box 44)
    - Vol. 21 (Box 45)
    - Vol. 22 (Box 45)
- Thirteenth Army Records, 1946
  - United Nations China Explanation, 1946
    - Vol. 1 (Box 24-26)
  - United Nations Properties Unit, 1946
    - Vol. 1 (Box 24-26)
    - Vol. 6 (Box 24-26)
    - Vol. 8 (Box 24-26)
    - Vol. 10 (Box 27-30)
    - Vol. 12 (Box 27-30)
  - Japanese Properties Unit, 1946
    - Vol. 1 (Box 31)
  - Chinese Properties Unit, 1946
    - Vol. 1 (Box 31)
    - Vol. 2 (Box 31)
    - Vol. 7 (Box 31)
  - Other Units, 1946
    - Vol. 34 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 36 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 40 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 41 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 42 (Box 46)
    - Vol. 43 (Box 46)
    - Vol. 44 (Box 46)
    - Vol. 45 (Box 46)
    - Vol. 47 (Box 46)
    - Vol. 48 (Box 46)
    - Vol. 49 (Box 47)
    - Vol. 50 (Box 47)
    - Vol. 51 (Box 47)
    - Vol. 52 (Box 47)
    - Vol. 53 (Box 48)
    - Vol. 54 (Box 48)
    - Vol. 55 (Box 48)
    - Vol. 56 (Box 48)
    - Vol. 57 (Box 49)
    - Vol. 58 (Box 49)
    - Vol. 59 (Box 49)
    - Vol.60 (Box 50)
    - Vol. 61 (Box 50)
    - Vol. 62 (Box 50)
- Twentieth Army Records, 1946
  - Other Units, 1946
    - Vol. 2 (Box 51)
- Twenty Third Army Records, 1946
  - United Nations Properties Unit, 1946
    - Vol. 1 (Box 51)
    - Vol. 2 (Box 51)
    - Vol. 3 (Box 51)
    - Vol. 4 (Box 51)
    - Vol. 5 (Box 51)
    - Appendix (Box 51)
- Forty Third Army Records, 1946
  - United Nations Properties Unit, 1946
    - Vol. 1 (Box 33-34, 51)
- Sixth Area Army Records, 1946
  - Other Units, 1946
    - Vol. 6 (Box 33-34, 51)
- North China Area Army-District Control Army Records, 1946
  - Other Units, 1946
    - Unnumbered (Box 35-38, 52)
    - Vol. 2 (Box 35-38, 52)
    - Vol. 3 (Box 35-38, 52)
    - Vol. 32 (Box 35-38, 52)
    - Vol. 33 (Box 35-38, 52)
- Chinese Army Records, 1946
  - Railway Unit, 1946
    - Vol. 2 (Box 39-40)
    - Vol. 3 (Box 39-40)
    - Vol. 4 (Box 39-40)
    - Vol. 6 (Box 35-38, 52)
    - Vol. 8 (Box 35-38, 52)
  - Maps, 1946
    - No. 6-3 (Box 35-38, 52)